删除大黄蜂 再替换上…
Removing Bumblebee and replacing him with...
踢踏舞猴子再度登场！
The tap-dancing monkey strikes again.
大黄蜂在互联网上抛头露面不是什么好笑的事
Bumblebee sightings on the world wide web are no laughing matter.
7 8 9…
7... 8... 9...
我就不能只开车吗？
Why can't I just drive from now on?
要是不用你的腿 它们会萎缩的
Because your legs will atrophy if you choose not to use them.
噢…
Oh...
1 2 3…
1... 2... 3...
等等 那是什么？
Wait. What's that?
塞博特恩的逃生舱？
A Cybertronian escape pod?
在地球大气层里？
Here in Earth's atmosphere?
汽车人还是霸天虎？
Autobot or Decepticon?
图片很模糊 没法辨认
Impossible to tell, given the image resolution.
不管哪种情况我们都应调查一番
In any event, this merits investigation.
没准是个圈套 此外我们还倒下一位
Could be a trap, and we're down one bot.
需要联系千斤顶吗？
Should we reach out to Wheeljack?
我听到了…
I can hear you!
我不管隔板是否能参加战斗
I don't care if Bulkhead isn't combat-ready.
鉴于上次千斤顶和神子一手导演的复仇大戏 他还是去当世外高人吧
After that revenge stunt he pulled with Miko, Wheeljack can stay rogue.
可能是一个遇难的汽车人
An Autobot may be in distress.
救护车 带上你的医疗箱
Ratchet, bring your medical kit.
是霸天虎那边的
It is of Decepticon origin.
里面的虎子已经跑路了
And the Con inside blew his way out.
那些虎子都是从一个舱里生出来的？
All those Cons came out of one pod?
按人类的说法 这是“英雄妈妈”
The humans refer to the phenomenon as a clown car.
有人过来了！
Incoming!
前面的趴下！
Down in front!
自己人？
Friendly?
后退！
Fall back!
哇噢 烫不烫 虎子们？
Whoo! Too hot for you, Cons?!
你的朋友？
Friend of yours?
从没见过他
Never seen him before.
点燃泄漏的能量
Torching that Energon leak.
我的点子不错吧？
Pretty good plan, right?
只不过那不是你的点子
Except that it wasn't your plan.
那不过是流弹造成的 而且差点连我们也一起烤糊了
It was a random shot that almost fried us to a crisp.
它管用了 不是吗？
Worked out, didn't it?
谢谢你 汽车人同伴
Thank you, fellow Autobot.
你的…勇气值得嘉奖
Your... valor... is to be commended.
我…难以置信！
I... don't believe it.
你是擎天柱！他是擎天柱！
Y-You're Optimus Prime! He's Optimus Prime!
- 我们知道\N- 是啊是的
- We know.\N- Yes, yes... yes.
你叫什么名字 战士？
What is your name, soldier?
烟幕 长官！
Smokescreen, sir.
欢迎来到地球 烟幕！
Welcome to Earth, Smokescreen.
来到这里是我的荣幸
It's an honor to be here...
尤其是能与您并肩战斗
Especially with you.
现在呢？我们不可能就这么带他回基地
Now what? It's not like we can just bring him back to base.
我们有过被间谍“鱼目混珠”的先例
Wouldn't be the first time an ally turned out to be a plant.
看起来你在塞博特恩的精英卫队中接受过训练
I see that you received your training from Cybertron's Elite Guard.
没错 不过那儿和新兵训练营差不多
True enough... though it wasn't more than a boot camp by the time I joined.
连个像样的毕业典礼都没有
I never even got a proper graduation ceremony.
那是在战争时期！
There was a war going on.
嘿 我不过是想成为一名战士
Hey, all I ever wanted was to be a soldier
为汽车人事业而献身
serve the Autobot cause.
不过我最终却成为了一名铁堡的保安特遣队员！
But what I got was security detail at Iacon.
中央档案馆？
The Hall of Records of all places?
擎天柱 你不觉得这很可疑吗？
Optimus, do you not find this highly suspicious?
烟幕 你在档案馆的任务是什么？
Smokescreen, what was your assignment inside the hall?
当战争进入末期时负责护卫钛师傅
Guarding Alpha Trion during what turned out to be the final days of the war.
你直属于主档案保管员？
You served under the master archivist?
刚开始我很不开心
Eh, I wasn't thrilled at first...
不能去痛扁虎子 却要看着一个老头的背影
watching the back of an old bot instead of kicking Con tailpipe.
对不起 不过钛师傅真的是个良师…益友
Sorry. But the big "A" turned out to be a great teacher and a... true friend.
我是说 就是他在最高议会面前推举你为领袖的
I mean, he was the one who petitioned Halogen and the High Council to make you a Prime.
拉斐尔 启动环陆桥
Rafael... activate the ground bridge.
这就行了？
That's it?
就凭这几句话你就让他入伙了？
That's all you need to hear before inviting him to the party?
既然我的导师愿意与他分享这些信息
If my former mentor shared this information
就足以证明烟幕是可以信赖的伙伴
it is because he considered Smokescreen a trusted ally.
在千斤顶之后我们就再也没有新人入伙了！
We haven't had somebody new here since Wheeljack.
你的故事 烟幕？
What's your story, Smoke?
你从哪里来？怎么到这儿的？
Where'd you come from? How'd you get here?
你带了多少武器？
How many blasters you packin'?
这些就是我们要保护的生物？
So, these are the life-force we're supposed to protect?
他们都是这个样子的？
Are they all like this?
幸运的是并非如此
Fortunately not...
不过我和神子一样好奇你是怎么来到地球的？
but I too share Miko's fascination with how you came to arrive on Earth.
搭一艘霸天虎的逃生舱
In a Decepticon escape pod.
还是不信任我是吧？真难相处
Still got trust issues, huh? Tough crowd.
主战斗地点离档案馆至少有20公里
The main thrust of combat operations was at least 20 clicks from the Hall of Records
所以那里一度很平静
so things had been pretty quiet.
然而局势很快便急转直下
But the situation went downhill fast.
虎子们发动了一次大规模攻击\N击溃了铁堡外部的最后防线
The Cons launched a massive surge that wiped out the last line of defenses surrounding Iacon.
我是最后一个可以进行抵抗的人
I was the only thing left to them back
我得说 我尽力了！
and, let me tell you, I was pumped.
我是说 这是我第一次有机会参见真正的战斗！
I mean, this was my chance to see real action for the first time...
来证明我自己
to prove myself.
直到我失去了意识
Until everything went black.
虎子们俘获了我 并将我绑到一艘运输船上
Cons took me prisoner and dumped me onto a transport ship.
不过我趁守卫不备钻进了一个逃生舱
But I managed to give a guard the slip and hopped in an escape pod.
很显然这是一个长距离逃生舱 它令我进入了休眠状态
Apparently, it was a long-distance pod, 'cause it knocked me into stasis.
等到我再次醒来的时候 正好重重摔落在地上
Next thing I knew, I'm hitting solid ground... hard.
霸天虎的战舰一定识别了逃生舱的信号\N并引导它来到了地球！
The Decepticon warship must have picked up pod's beacon and guided it to Earth.
这就解释了虎子们为什么会来迎接烟幕
Which would explain Smokescreen's welcoming committee.
那些虎子发现里面不是他们的同伙一定很失望
Bet those Cons were disappointed not to find one of their own inside.
烟幕 你知道在铁堡失守后
Smokescreen, do you know of Alpha Ttrion's fate
钛师傅怎么样了吗？
after the fall of Iacon?
我也想知道
I wish I did.
不过那是我最后一次见到他老人家
But that was the last I ever saw of him.
这就是我的故事
That's it... my life story.
不像我梦想的那般荣耀
Not exactly the glory I envisioned for myself
不过现在
... until now.
跟擎天柱在一起？
Being here with Optimus Prime...
我就知道我注定是块做大事的料
I knew I was destined for great things.
我是说 现在你有帮手了
I mean, now that you have help
结束这场战争能有多困难？
how hard could it be to end this war?
好好看看这个 新来的！
Take a good look, Newbie.
就有这么难！
This is how hard.
烟幕 我建议你花点时间适应下新环境
Smokescreen, I would suggest that you take some time to become acclimated to your new surroundings.
参观下基地是个不错的开始
A tour of the base would be an excellent start.
没问题！
Sure thing!
我的意思是 杰克可以提供一个内容丰富的旅程
I mean... Jack here offers a very informative tour.
这就是人类所谓的信息高速公路
This is what the humans call "the information superhighway".
一万亿个字节 没一个有用的！
A trillion gigabytes of data... none of it's useful!
尽管有些吸引人的奇怪东西
Though some oddly engrossing.
这是什么？
What is this?
啊… 愚蠢的生命体不知道他们找到的是什么
Ah... ignorant life-forms have no idea what they've uncovered.
红色能量
Red Energon.
如果我能拥有它的力量
If I can possess its power
我不仅能变得更强壮 也能变得更快
not only will I be stronger but also faster.
大大的加快！
Significantly faster.
相位仪 火种剥离器 静止器
Phase shifter... Spark extractor... Immobilizer...
这里保存的都是我们找到的埋藏在地球上的遗物
this is where we store the Cybertronian relics we found buried on Earth.
说起来世界真是小 因为这些大部分都来自…
And talk about a small universe 'cause most of them came from the...
铁堡档案馆
The Iacon hall of records.
我记得这些
I remember these.
哇哦！她算哪种遗物？
Whoa. What kind of relic is she?
你最好别招惹的那种
The kind you don't want to mess with.
如果你们想换掉我 最好叫千斤顶来！
If you wanted to replace me, you should have called Wheeljack.
那样我还能好受些
I could have lived with that.
没人要换掉你 隔板
No one is replacing you, Bulkhead.
况且烟幕还是个楞头青
For one thing, Smokescreen's too green.
隔板也够青
Well, Bulk's as green as they get.
阿尔茜的意思是
What Arcee means is...
烟幕需要学习的事情还有很多！
Smokescreen still has a great deal to learn.
那训练好他之后呢？
And once you got him trained, then what, huh?
他入伍？我退役？
He's in. I'm a doorstop.
隔板 你在我们中的位置不会受到任何影响
Bulkhead, your place with us is not in jeopardy
但毫无疑问的是 我们长久以来缺乏战斗力
but there is no dispute that we have long required additional firepower.
对于我们的队伍来说 现在应学会接纳新人
It is essential that our team learns to work with our new recruit
而不是排斥他
not against him.
但愿这小子的枪跟嘴一样厉害
Better hope the hotshot's blasters are as big as his mouth.
这有什么难的…
How hard can it be?
嘿 伙计们 看看这个
Hey, everyone. Check this out.
别告诉我又是大黄蜂目击新闻！哦 天啊！
But don't tell me it's another Bumblebee sight... oh my.
红色能量
Red Energon.
在地球上？
Here... on Earth?
红色能量是什么？
What's Red Energon?
一种十分稀有且极不稳定的能量形式
An extremely rare and volatile form of Energellum.
提炼出的燃料可以提供超高速
Refined into fuel, it provides the power of hyperspeed.
我们必须联系福勒探员 让他疏散挖掘地点附近的所有人类
We must have Agent Fowler clear the dig site of all human presence
我们不可能是唯一发现这个地点的人
in the event we are not the only ones who have discovered its location.
说得好
Now you're talking.
我们去打烂虎子的电路！
Let's scramble up some Cons' circuits.
鉴于你的实战经验有限
Given your limited field experience
我认为在参加战斗之前 你有必要接受更多的训练
I believe further training is required before you are battle-ready.
擎天柱 恕我直言…
Optimus, with all due respect...
此外 我们汽车人在地球上需要隐蔽
Furthermore, we Autobots live on this planet as robots in disguise.
你需要扫描一个地球的车辆形态
You will need to obtain an Earth-based vehicle mode.
为了保持低调行动
In order to maintain a low profile...
如果你能做得到的话
if that's possible for you.
你是说变车是吧？没问题！
If you're talking wheels, bring 'em on!
红色能量是我的 人类！
The Red Energon is mine, humans!
你们毫无胜算 因为你们面对的是伟大的红蜘…
For you are powerless in the face of the mighty Star...
什么？
What?
它哪儿去了？
Where is it?
不行
Nope.
那个怎么样？
How about that one?
呃 那速度更适合救护车 你不觉得吗？
Eh, it's more Ratchet's speed, don't you think?
水泥车？
Cement truck?
好吧 除非我是个挖地虎
Yeah, if I were a Constructicon.
老实说 这就是你们星球最拿得出手的？
Seriously, this is the best your planet has to offer?
不 这里毕竟是贾斯帕
No, but this is Jasper.
我找到了
I feel for you.
福勒就不能用吊车把它放下来吗？
Fowler couldn't have the crane operator lower the thing?
一定是人类准备把陨石装上货轮的时候
The humans must have been preparing to transfer the meteor to a cargo ship
接到了疏散指令
when they received his evacuation order.
滚回去 汽车人！
Run along home, Autobots.
那个红色能量本座指名要了！
That Red Energon has my name all over it.
并且我不惜为它而战！
And I am more than willing to fight for it.
夺取红色能量 叫救护车把它传送回基地
Secure the Red Energon and have Ratchet bridge it back to base.
别告诉我你忘了我们上次的交手了 擎天柱！
Don't tell me you've already forgotten our last encounter, Prime.
继续前进 小蜂！
Keep moving, Bee.
擎天柱 出什么情况了吗？
Optimus, is something wrong?
红蜘蛛来抢夺红色能量
Starscream has come for the Red Energon
恐怕没法让他打消这个念头
and I fear he will not be deterred in his quest.
红蜘蛛？我在塞博特恩听说过那个穿高跟鞋的家伙
Starscream? I heard stories about that stiletto-heeled creep back on Cybertron.
让我过去 医生！
Send me in, Doc.
如果擎天柱需要救援 他会提出的
When Optimus requires backup, he will ask for it.
噢 拜托 我已经准备好车辆形态了
Aw, come on. I got my V-mode and everything.
开足马力就等着出发了
I'm souped up and ready to roll.
打住！打住！
Eh! Eh! Eh!
更多的训练你听不懂吗？
What part of "further training" did you not understand?
爬得越高 摔得越惨！
The higher you climb, the harder you fall.
哈哈 汽车人 总是不长记性
Haha. Autobots... such slow learners.
擎天柱 你的情况怎么样？
Optimus, what is your status?
救护车 他们需要我 我能行的！
Ratchet, they need me. I can do this.
阿尔茜？大黄蜂？
Arcee? Bumblebee?
你听到我在说话了吗？
Did you hear what I said?
我听到了 但是没有理睬你
I heard, and I'm ignoring you.
看来你终于有机会了 烟幕…
This may be your opportunity after all, Smokescre...
烟幕呢？
Where is Smokescreen?
就是这个
That's the one.
你！
You, there!
看在火种源的份上 你知道你在做什么吗？
What in the name of the Allspark do you think you're doing?
要扔些重物下去了
Time to unload some more deadweight.
站稳了 汽车人！
Watch your step, Autobots!
很显然没人告诉他“低调”是什么意思
Apparently, no one defined "low profile" for him.
看来 汽车人有个新兵蛋子
So, the Autobots have a new recruit.
你就是红蜘蛛啊
And you must be Starscream.
还以为有多高大呢
I thought you'd be taller.
这下可不好收场了
This will not end well.
烟幕 退下！
Smokescreen, stand down.
你敌不过红蜘蛛的精锐护甲
You are no match for Starscream's Apex armor.
有什么遗言吗 烟幕？
Any last words, Smokescreen?
八个字：和你的盔甲吻别吧
Just four: kiss your armor goodbye!
相位仪？
A Phase shifter?
这可是个好点子！
Now, that was a plan!
你可不是唯一一个带着腕式装备的人！
You aren't the only one sporting a fancy wrist-mounted device.
动动脑筋吧！
Think fast!
不！
No!
都说了不过是借用一会儿！
Told you I just needed to borrow it for a while.
医生却认为我要偷你们的遗物
Doc here thought I was trying to steal your relics.
除非你先解释你的计划
Only until you explained your plan
而后得到我的批准
which I then sanctioned.
这叫做协议
It's called protocol.
救护车是对的
Ratchet is correct.
规则适用于队伍中的所有成员
Standard procedure must be observed by every member of this team.
不过 我相信烟幕是值得称赞的
However... I believe we must also commend Smokescreen.
你在选择策略制造声势方面学习的很快
You have proven to be a quick study by choosing to place strategy above bravado.
看来要开始和他一起生活了
There is gonna be no living with him now.
虽然这个仪式不如精英卫队那样壮观
While this may lack the pageantry of a proper Elite Guard ceremony
我真诚地欢迎你加入领袖卫队！
I wish to welcome you to team Prime.
这个新人确实干得不赖…
The Newbie did all right.
别担心 小隔
Don't worry, Bulk.
他不会抢你的饭碗的！
He's got nothing on you.
真的 一旦你的腿伤愈复出了
Seriously, once we get that leg of yours back in shape
烟幕就会知道谁是这里最强的粉碎球了！
old Smokey's gonna learn real quick who the top wrecking ball is run here.
隔板？
Bulkhead?